http://www.htsc.org.uk/privacy

Pastoral care
First time in Church?
Running the church
Can you help?
Pastoral care
First time in Church?
Running the church
Can you help?
Data privacy notice
The Rector and Parochial Church Council (PCC) of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield
1. Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the GDPR) 2018 and the Data Protection Act 2018.
2. Who are we?
The PCC of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield, and the Rector of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield, are each Data Controllers (contact details below). This means that they decide how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
3. How do we process your personal data?
The Rector and the PCC of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield comply with their obligations under the GDPR by collecting and storing personal data legally, keeping it up to date; storing and destroying it securely; protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by allowing you as a Data Subject to exercise your right to opt out of data processing or to request a copy of data held about you.
We use your personal data for the following purposes: -To enable us to provide Christian ministry, services and pastoral care within the Church of England and the Diocese of Birmingham
To administer membership records of the church, known as the Electoral Roll
To enable people to be married, baptised, confirmed or funerals to be held, and registers kept to comply with legal requirements
To safeguard children, young people, vulnerable adults and all at Holy Trinity
To fundraise and promote the interests of the church, which is a registered charity, and for other charities chosen each year
To manage our employees and volunteers
To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications)
To inform you of news, events, activities and services running at Holy Trinity
4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
The Rector and PCC of Holy Trinity may process your data on a variety of legal bases:
Where you have a contract, such as hire of church premises or sale of event tickets
Where there is a legal requirement to hold the data – such as gift aid, marriage and baptism records, Electoral Roll
Legitimate interests – if you are a regular church member, committee member or volunteer we will keep you informed about church events, meetings and rotas. If you have provided personal data about a marriage or baptism, this will be used to make arrangements for the event
Vital interests – if you have a life-threatening medical emergency, we may disclose personal data if we have it such as date of birth, next of kin and medical details to emergency services if this would help your care
Consent – if none of the above conditions apply, we will ask for your consent to process your data
Some of the data we process may fall under the ‘special categories’ of data, mainly religious belief, and medical conditions for children or vulnerable adults. Special care will be taken with this data and it will not be shared outside the church without your consent
For data about children – the new Regulations state that young people aged 13 and over can give their own consent; younger children must have consent given by a parent or carer
5. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to church members or for purposes connected with the church. Data may be shared between the PCC and the Rector, other church officers (officers may be staff or volunteers) and the Diocese of Birmingham.
Data may be shared with other bodies for legal purposes; for example details of your gift aid donations will be shared with HM Revenue and Customs for the purpose of claiming a tax refund, and details of those married in church will be shared with the Register Office; checks for volunteers may be made to the Disclosure and Barring Service (DBS).
Storing your personal data
Your data may be held in the Parish Office or the Rectory office, but In common with many other organisations which rely on a large number of volunteers, some personal data will be held by members of the church in their homes. The Data Protection Policy ensures that this data is held, processed and deleted securely. Your data might be stored or processed on secure third party systems.
6. How long do we keep your personal data?
This varies depending on the data. In general, data will be deleted once it is no longer current or needed.
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently. Information related to safeguarding may be kept for up to 75 years.
7. Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –
The right to request a copy of your personal data which the Rector or the PCC of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield hold about you
The right to request that the Rector or the PCC of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Rector PCC of Holy Trinity, Sutton Coldfield to retain such data – note that there are legal reasons why this may not be possible
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.
8. Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Privacy Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing. Where necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
9. Contact Details
To exercise your rights under section 7 above, or for any Data Protection queries or complaints, please contact: the Trinity Centre, Church Hill, Mill Street, Sutton Coldfield, West Midlands, B72 1TF. Email dataprotection@htsc.org.uk or telephone (0121) 321 1144. If writing or telephoning please state that your query relates to data protection.
You can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
Final version approved by PCC 19.6.18
Google Analytics Addendum
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files saved on your computer, to help the website analyze how you use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. If this website anonymizes IP addresses, your IP address will be truncated by Google within a EU member state or other EEA state before being transmitted to the US. Only in exceptional situations will your full IP address be transmitted to Google servers in the United States and truncated there. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You can also prevent Google from collecting information (including your IP address) via cookies and processing this information by downloading this browser plugin and installing it: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
You can prevent data collection via Google Analytics by clicking here. An “Opt-out Cookie” shall then be applied to your website which shall prevent any future collection of your data when visiting this website.
Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at the Google Analytics Terms of Service or at the Google Analytics Privacy Overview. Please note that on this website, Google Analytics is supplemented by “gat._anonymizeIp();” to ensure anonymized collection of IP addresses (IP masking).
reCAPTCHA
We use the reCAPTCHA service provided by Google Inc. (Google) to protect your submissions via internet submission forms on this site. This plugin checks if you are a person in order to prevent certain website functions from being (ab)used by spam bots (particularly comments). This plugin query includes the sending of the IP address and possibly other data required by Google for the Google reCAPTCHA service. For this purpose your input will be communicated to and used by Google. However, your IP address is previously truncated by Google within member states of the European Union or in other states which are party to the agreement on the European Economic Area and is, as such, anonymized. Only in exceptional cases is a full IP address transmitted to a Google server in the United States and truncated there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of this service. The IP address provided by reCaptcha from your browser shall not be merged with any other data from Google.
This data collection is subject to the data protection regulations of Google (Google Inc.). For more information about Google’s privacy policy, please visit: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/
By using the reCAPTCHA service, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
Church Hill,
Mill St,
Sutton Coldfield,
West Midlands,
Notice: JavaScript is required for this content.
